<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab Manual | LMCL</title>
    <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Lab Manual</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./img/logo3.png</url>
      <title>Lab Manual</title>
      <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Calendars</title>
      <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/calendars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/calendars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab uses and maintains three Google Calendars to books and schedule the three rooms in BPS 3150.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those three calendars are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LMCL 3150A&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LMCL 3150B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LMCL 3150G&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also use google calendars to reserve the EEG suite in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ncdl.umd.edu/&#34;&gt;NCDL&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPS 2109 E&amp;amp;F (testing &amp;amp; control rooms)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPS 2019 conference room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and the BIOPAC lab in the basement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BPS 0127&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for access to the calendars relevant to you, ask Dr. Slevc to share them with your gmail account. Once you have access, you can reserve the desired room by simply adding an event with your name as the subject from the time you need in the desired room&amp;rsquo;s calendar.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Info for LMCL Research Assistants</title>
      <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/ra_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/ra_info/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve complied lots of relevant information for research assistants in the lab into a syllabus for PSYC 479. This is, of course, highly relevant if you&amp;rsquo;re enrolled in 479, but most of this applies to any RA, whether or not working for course credit. Please take a look!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PSYC 479 – Special Research Problems in Psychology&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Syllabus for &lt;a href=&#34;https://lmcl-umd.github.io/&#34;&gt;Language and Music Cognition Lab&lt;/a&gt; Research Assistants&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://lmcl-umd.github.io/files/PSYC479_Slevc_syllabus_12-15-21.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF version of the syllabus&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lab location:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; BPS 3150
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructor / Lab PI:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Dr. &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyc.umd.edu/facultyprofile/slevc/l-robert&#34;&gt;L. Robert Slevc (he/him)&lt;/a&gt; – &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:slevc@umd.edu&#34;&gt;slevc@umd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This directed study will provide the opportunity to participate in behavioral and/or neuroscientific research projects in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lmcl-umd.github.io/&#34;&gt;UMD Language and Music Cognition Lab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific projects you will be involved with will be based on your interests and background combined with the needs of current projects. Your specific responsibilities will also vary depending on the stage of the relevant research project. You might assist with behavioral, EEG, and/or MEG data collection (including preparing for participant lab visits and cleaning up afterwards), recruiting and scheduling participants, data coding, data entry, and/or assisting with data analyses. You may also be asked to perform literature searches, write reports of research findings, and write short blogposts for a general audience on recent research relevant to the lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By assisting with research in our lab, you will gain technical and theoretical research skills, interpersonal skills (by working with lab members and human participants), and skills associated with research communication and dissemination. You will also learn about procedures and policies that protect research participants. You will be a contributing member to ongoing research on the cognitive and neural processes involved in language and/or music perception and production. Student involvement in research is critical to much of the scientific work done here at Maryland and we value your commitment to maintaining the high quality of our research process. During this experience, you will learn about theory and current literature in psycholinguistics/neurolinguistics and music perception and cognition. You will also learn more generally about theories and behavioral and neuroscience methods involved in cognitive science / cognitive psychology research. We hope that your experience working in this research lab is rewarding and useful in your academic career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Master a selected bibliography of scientific literature related to your project(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop research technology skills through hands on experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop scientific communication skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate and pursue science-related career development opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervisors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your primary research mentor is Dr. Slevc, the lab&#39;s PI. However, your immediate supervisor / research mentor may be a graduate student or postdoc depending on the specific projects you are working on. Research mentors will supervise your work and are available for lab-related and other questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course Requirements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Enrolling for three credits commits you to 135 hours of work (an average of 9 hours/week) on the project(s) to which you are assigned. (Enrolling for two credits may also be possible, which would commit you to 90 hours, or an average of 6 hours/week.) Scheduled hours are typically flexible, although the degree of flexibility can vary by research project. In general, you should schedule your specific hours at least a week in advance, and ideally farther in advance if posting timeslots for participant signups.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It is important to keep up with your hours. If research tasks are not filling these hours (e.g., because of limited participant signups or pandemic-related research restrictions) then you are expected to work with your instructor to identify other useful ways to contribute (e.g., by working on literature reviews, documenting / writing up aspects of the research, etc.) Students who fall behind in hours can make up time during finals week if necessary, depending on the availability of lab work at the end of the semester. If you get significantly behind in your hours (&amp;amp;gt;10 hours behind where you should be in the term), you should work with your supervisor to make arrangements for completing your hours on time.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;When running experiments:&lt;/em&gt; One of the most important aspects of a position in a research lab is collecting data (i.e., running experiments). It is crucial that you respect participants&#39; time by being on time yourself and being prepared when running an experiment Your grade will be affected if you are late or miss an assigned shift (see details below in the &amp;quot;Grading&amp;quot; section).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Training / certifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It is important that you understand how to protect the rights and welfare of research participants. Thus, before becoming involved in research on human participants, you should first complete an online research ethics course from the CITI program. To do this, create an account at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citiprogram.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.citiprogram.org&lt;/a&gt; and take the online &amp;quot;Social and Behavioral Basic/Refresher&amp;quot; course (be sure to put &amp;quot;University of Maryland, College Park&amp;quot; as an affiliation). Once complete, you should turn in a copy of your completion report. If you have taken this course already (e.g., for experience in another lab) within the past three years, you need not take again. (If it has been over three years, you can take a shorter &amp;quot;refresher&amp;quot; course – contact instructor for details.)
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Various other training courses and/or meetings may be required depending on the specific project(s) you are involved with. These meetings will count toward your lab hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading assignments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. You will periodically be asked to read materials related to your projects in the lab and/or about psycholinguistic / neurolinguistic research more generally. You may also be asked to read and comment on lab members&#39; work-in-progress, workshop presentations, etc. When lab work is relatively slow (e.g., because of minimal participant signups), a good use of time is to catch up on the background reading listed below and on past published work from the lab (linked on the lab webpage).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weekly lab meetings.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; Weekly lab meetings are required and count towards your total hours in the lab. These meetings provide opportunities to discuss ongoing research projects, giving you greater context for the projects you are working on. These also are valuable in that other lab members can get feedback from you and other lab members on their work. We also may use these meetings to discuss papers or topics of professional development. We welcome suggestions and requests for these meetings. For Spring, 2022, lab meetings are scheduled for &lt;strong&gt;Thursdays at 4pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final assignment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; The &amp;quot;standard&amp;quot; final assignment is to contribute at least one post to &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/langmuscoglab&#34;&gt;the lab&#39;s blog&lt;/a&gt;. This post should describe the findings of some resent research that you find interesting and is related (at least tangentially) to the lab&#39;s work (i.e., a recent primary source article about language and/or music perception/cognition). It should target an intelligent, but non-expert, audience and, ideally, should also refer to additional relevant sources. More details and some resources for this assignment are posted &lt;a href=&#34;https://lmcl-umd.github.io/doc/example/bloginfo/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This post is due by the last day of classes (unless you ask for an extension), although you are &lt;em&gt;strongly&lt;/em&gt; encouraged to complete this earlier in the semester so that you can present it in a lab meeting to get feedback and suggestions.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If you do not wish to write and publish a blogpost, you can instead lead a lab meeting on some topic relevant to the lab. You may also negotiate some other assignment. In any case, you are encouraged to talk with your research mentor or Dr. Slevc before beginning the assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grading&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your supervisors (e.g., graduate student research mentor, the lab manager, and Dr. Slevc) will evaluate your reliability, professionalism, initiative, teamwork, punctuality, positive work attitude, communication, promptness in completing tasks, thoroughness, and knowledge of job. Grades will then be assigned based on your hours completed and the quality of your work as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completion of hours 60%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final Assignment 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervisors&#39; Evaluation 30%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Course policies and other notes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is subject to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ugst.umd.edu/courserelatedpolicies.html&#34;&gt;university-wide policies for undergraduate courses&lt;/a&gt;. These include policies on academic integrity, student conduct, sexual misconduct, discrimination, accessibility, attendance, absences, missed assignments, student rights, official UMD communications, midterm grades, complaints about final exams, copyright and intellectual property, final exams, course evaluations, and campus resources. A few other topics specific to this class:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidentiality.&lt;/strong&gt; Data we collect is provided by our research participants with the understanding that their identity will remain confidential. Protecting participants&#39; identity and maintaining confidentiality is critical to ethical research. As a research assistant, you may have access to confidential material and it is very important that you do not discuss this information outside the lab. Confidential lab materials should not be removed from the lab and you should not discuss participants outside of necessary discussion for research purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of email and Slack for official communication.&lt;/strong&gt; Prompt communication is essential for an efficient lab environment. You will be expected to reply to emails about lab matters or (more often) messages on the lab Slack channel within 24 hours (48 hours on weekends). Frequent delayed responses could lower your course grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graduate school / Career planning.&lt;/strong&gt; Any students who would like to discuss graduate school or careers in psychology are encouraged to meet with graduate students, postdocs, or Dr. Slevc for input/advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scholarly work.&lt;/strong&gt; We encourage students who are interested in investing time, energy, and intellectual contributions above and beyond their lab responsibilities to consider taking on their own project (or aspects of a larger project). This could lead to an honors thesis, result in presenting research locally or at national/international conferences, and even result in co-authoring publications. Please be aware that the opportunity for this level of intellectual contribution and involvement depends not only on your initiative and investment, but also on the opportunities that are currently available.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Students are encouraged to consider presenting either their independent research or other (non-independent) research with which they are involved at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyc.umd.edu/undergraduate/undergraduate-research-day&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;PSYC Undergraduate Research Day&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in the Spring. If you do this, we expect that you will spend lab hours working on aspects of the project. However, you should expect that planning a presentation will require effort beyond your lab hours, as this is something done for your own professional development. Students can present independently or part of a team depending on their level of experience in the lab and the type of projects available. Students often find this to be an engaging and rewarding experience and we hope you will too.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
There are often opportunities for summer funding to work on independent research through BSOS and through the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mcur.umd.edu/&#34;&gt;Maryland Center for Undergraduate Research&lt;/a&gt;. If you are interested in pursuing these types of opportunities, please discuss with your lab supervisors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letters of recommendation.&lt;/strong&gt; Dr. Slevc will generally write a letter of recommendation for students who have committed at least two semesters of 3-credits (or 9 hours) to the lab and have performed well. You should ask for the letter well in advance of the deadline. Please realize that the strength of a letter carries more weight than the mere &lt;em&gt;presence&lt;/em&gt; of a letter. Factors that contribute to a stronger letter include demonstrating initiative and investment in the lab and the projects you are working on, consistent reliability and accountability in your lab hours and projects, and a strong ability to work collaboratively with lab members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Illness.&lt;/strong&gt; Please do not come into the lab if you are sick. It is better to cancel an experimental session or fall behind than to risk getting the rest of the lab (and experimental participants) sick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complaints or problems.&lt;/strong&gt; If something is not going as well as you would like, &lt;em&gt;please tell someone&lt;/em&gt; about it. Talk to your research mentor, the lab manager, or another lab member you feel comfortable with. The lab environment and procedures are always evolving and can always be improved, but we can only improve things if we know what isn&#39;t going well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#sdfootnote1anc&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; Often it is not possible to find a time for lab meeting where everyone is available, in which case we prioritize new lab members and lab members who were not able to meet at a lab meeting the last semester. If this leaves you unable to attend, then of course lab meeting attendance is not required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSYC 479 | Spring, 2022 | syllabus version of 12/15/21&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The LMCL Blog</title>
      <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/bloginfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/bloginfo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The LMCL now maintains a blog, hosted by Medium. If you&amp;rsquo;re enrolled in PSYC 479, one option for your &amp;lsquo;final paper&amp;rsquo; is to contribute a blog post about some topic related to language and/or music cognition that you find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog can be found at our lab &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/langmuscoglab&#34;&gt;publication section&lt;/a&gt; on Medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, these posts should:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;describe the findings of a recent primary source article about music perception/cognition (ideally referring to additional relevant sources as well).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;target an intelligent, but non-expert, audience. Consider the advice &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.americanscientist.org/blog/from-the-staff/12-tips-for-scientists-writing-for-the-general-public&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could find recent interesting and relevant work in lots of ways. If you have a topic in mind, try &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.google.com/&#34;&gt;google scholar&lt;/a&gt; (I suggest you constrain your search to the last year or two). If you have an older paper you&amp;rsquo;re interested in, try a cited reference search (click &amp;ldquo;Cited by&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; under the google scholar result for that paper) to see if there&amp;rsquo;s some newer relevant research that you could include. And if you don&amp;rsquo;t yet have a topic in mind, try browsing recent tables of contents from some journals that publish relevant research &amp;ndash; here are some suggestions (though definitely not an exhaustive list - and note that you may need on-campus or proxy access to get some of these journals):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/brain-and-language&#34;&gt;Brain &amp;amp; Language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/journal/cognition&#34;&gt;Cognition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mitpressjournals.org/ljoi/jocn&#34;&gt;Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://psycnet.apa.org/PsycARTICLES/journal/xlm/45/11&#34;&gt;JEP:LMC&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://psycnet.apa.org/PsycARTICLES/journal/xhp/45/11&#34;&gt;JEP:HPP&lt;/a&gt; (note that you&amp;rsquo;ll annoyingly have to dig around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lib.umd.edu/dbfinder/id/UMD01529&#34;&gt;PsycINFO&lt;/a&gt; to get access to these articles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/toc/plcp21/current&#34;&gt;Language, Cognition and Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journals.elsevier.com/neuropsychologia&#34;&gt;Neuropsychologia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/home/pss&#34;&gt;Psychological Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/home/pom&#34;&gt;Psychology of Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychonomic.org/page/PBR&#34;&gt;Psychonomic Bulletin &amp;amp; Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s some basic info on &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/225168768-Write-post&#34;&gt;writing a post in Medium&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/213904978-Add-draft-or-post-to-publication&#34;&gt;adding your post to the lab publication&lt;/a&gt;, and on &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.medium.com/hc/en-us/articles/214981378-Embeds&#34;&gt;embedding content&lt;/a&gt; in your post. (note: please un-check &amp;ldquo;Allow curators to recommend my story&amp;rdquo; when you publish.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, here are a few examples of (IMHO) good relevant science writing. You should, of course, find your own voice, but here you can find examples of the type of writing we&amp;rsquo;re hoping for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mpi-talkling.mpi.nl/&#34;&gt;MPI TalkLing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://theamericanscholar.org/daily-scholar/psycho-babble/&#34;&gt;PsychoBabble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://featuredcontent.psychonomic.org/&#34;&gt;Psychonomic Society blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vicky Williamson&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://musicpsychology.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Music Psychology blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and many more (please send me suggestions if you have &amp;lsquo;em!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy writing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LMCL iMac Computers</title>
      <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/imacsoftware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/imacsoftware/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-about-the-imac-computers-in-the-lab&#34;&gt;Information about the iMac computers in the lab&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to update the software on the iMac Computers, you have to first check the compatibility with the version number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can go to The Apple icon in the top left corner &amp;gt; About This Mac&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model number will tell you when the iMac was released and the version number will tell you what version of OS your computer is running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the computer is running software 10.7 or below, you will have to go online and download and install the next version of software yourself (rather than through the App Store).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To download El Capitan follow the instructions &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT206886&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To download High Sierra follow the instructions &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208969&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; Note: if the iMac is version 11,2 (i.e. mid 2010) or earlier, the highest OS you can upgrade to is High Sierra &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychopy Tips and Tricks</title>
      <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/psychopyupdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/psychopyupdate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-update-to-psychopy3-on-your-computer&#34;&gt;How to update to Psychopy3 on your computer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of 11/1/2019, the standalone package to download Psychopy3 from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychopy.org/download.html&#34;&gt;Psychopy website&lt;/a&gt; does not contain the correct dependencies required for using some of the features we need in the LMCL (such as the pyo library for audio and voice keys).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work around is to download the source code via the terminal and adjust the dependencies yourself. Instructions for this are outlined on the Psychopy website but require additional manipulation to work in the capacity required for this lab. Additional instructions have been outlined below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-mac-users&#34;&gt;For Mac users:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OS must be updated to version 10.12 or higher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;must be running python 3.6 or higher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use pip3 to install pyo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use pip3 to install pyglet == 1.2.4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the above is complete can you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;pip3 install psychopy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To now open and run psychopy3, open the command line terminal and simply type &amp;ldquo;psychopy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-pc-users&#34;&gt;For PC users:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow the instructions on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.psychopy.org/download.html&#34;&gt;Psychopy website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LMCL Website Overview</title>
      <link>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/editwebsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lmcl-umd.github.io./doc/example/editwebsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-design&#34;&gt;System Design:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LMCL website is built using a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/what-is-hugo/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; website framework and hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com&#34;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. We implemented the Hugo &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; theme. The Academic theme uses a series of templates called &amp;ldquo;widgets&amp;rdquo; that can copied and edited as needed to build the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our website is available at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://lmcl-umd.github.io&#34;&gt;http://lmcl-umd.github.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-requirements&#34;&gt;System Requirements:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to edit and update the website, you must have the following installed on your machine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Homebrew](https://brew.sh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Hugo](https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Git](https://help.github.com/en/github/getting-started-with-github/set-up-git)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;github-repositories&#34;&gt;Github Repositories:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code for our website is hosted on Github. The username for our lab&amp;rsquo;s GitHub is &lt;b&gt;lmcl-umd&lt;/b&gt;. Contact Dr. Slevc for the password if/when needed for SSH authentication (see &amp;ldquo;Editing the Website&amp;rdquo; below). There are two repositories in which the code lives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt; websiteWork&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; lmcl-umd.github.io.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;b&gt;websiteWork&lt;/b&gt; repository is where the working code lives while the &lt;b&gt;lmcl-umd.github.io.&lt;/b&gt; repository is where the live (published) code lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; Note: You will only ever have to change code in websiteWork and that will automatically update the live code in the lmcl-umd.github.io. repository. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;editingupdating-the-website&#34;&gt;Editing/Updating the Website:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to edit the website, you must clone the websiteWork repository from git onto your local machine. When you clone the websiteWork repository, the &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; folder from the code will also be copied onto your machine. This folder, in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms, manages the updates to the site repository. In order to clone and set up this automatic updating, you must follow the steps below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; open a terminal on your computer 
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; navigate to the folder&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;directory &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;in&lt;/span&gt; which you wish to download the websiteWork repository
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; use the following command to clone the websiteWork repository onto your local machine: 
git clone https:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;github&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;com&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;lmcl&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;umd&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;websiteWork&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;git
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; navigate into the websiteWork directory
cd websiteWork
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt; completely remove the current public directory so that you may set up your own tracking to the remote repository
git rm &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;r &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;cached public
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt; creates a git submodule, this builds your site to public where the created public directory will have a different remote origin (i&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;e&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; hosted GitHub repository)
git submodule add &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;b master git&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;@github&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;com:lmcl&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;umd&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;lmcl&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;umd&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;github&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;io&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;git public
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;7.&lt;/span&gt; run the first build of public
hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the website files are locally on your machine and your public directory is set up, you can make changes that will be visible both locally and on the master site. Any time you make changes in the local, websiteWork repository (any of the websiteWork files), you will follow the steps below to deploy these changes to the public repository (i.e. the website):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; make sure your local repository matches &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;with&lt;/span&gt; the remote repository, pull any new changes
git pull
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; see what changes have been made
git status
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; add all these changes to git &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; tracking
git add &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt; commit your changes to be made
git commit &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;m &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;your commit message here&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;5.&lt;/span&gt; push these changes to the local websiteWork repository 
git push
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;6.&lt;/span&gt; deploy these changes to the public repository (i&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;e&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; the live website)
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;./&lt;/span&gt;deploy&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;sh &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Your commit message&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This deploy command will push your edits to the lmcl-umd.github.io. repository and after a couple of minutes, your changes will appear on the live website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to clone and push edits via git, you must first have git set up on your computer and &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/en/github/authenticating-to-github/adding-a-new-ssh-key-to-your-github-account&#34;&gt;authenticate our lmcl-umd GitHub&lt;/a&gt; account via your computer&amp;rsquo;s unique SSH key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;helpful-git-commands&#34;&gt;Helpful Git Commands:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# clone the repository&lt;/span&gt;
git clone https:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;github&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;com&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;lmcl&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;umd&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;websiteWork&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;git

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# make sure you have the most recent version of the repository on your local machine&lt;/span&gt;
git pull

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# deploy edits to lmcl-umd.github.io. repository&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# your commit message should describe the edits made &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;./&lt;/span&gt;deploy&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;sh &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;your commit message&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# add edits to websiteWork repository&lt;/span&gt;
git add &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# commit edits to websiteWork repository&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# your commit message should describe the edits made &lt;/span&gt;
git commit &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;m &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;your commit message&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# push edits to websiteWork repository&lt;/span&gt;
git push 

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;# see what edits you have made&lt;/span&gt;
git staus 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;multiple-git-users&#34;&gt;Multiple Git Users:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are multiple users updating the website from multiple devices, the websiteWork repository on your local machine may be out of date from time to time. To ensure that you always have the most up to date version of the website code, you must &amp;ldquo;pull&amp;rdquo; it down from the repository &lt;b&gt;before&lt;/b&gt; you make any changes yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;git pull
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the output of this code carefully. If the word &amp;ldquo;error&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;aborting&amp;rdquo; is present after you try to pull the websiteWork repository, something went wrong. The most likely problem is that there are some untracked files between the two versions of code (the version in the repository and the version on your local machine) and git is unable to merge them. To resolve this issue, run the following two code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;git fetch &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;all
git reset &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;--&lt;/span&gt;hard origin&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, you should be able to run the pull command again and successfully get an updated version of the code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;git pull
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are still getting errors with pushing your local websiteWork repository or delaying the public repository, I recommend just deleting the repository all together and re-cloning (and setting up the public folder) from the beginning. It is very easy for git to become complicated and its easier to just start fresh with all the commits/branches up to date, which will be the case if you re-clone from remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you can make your own changes to any of the websiteWork files and deploy, git add, git commit, and git push as you normally would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-organization&#34;&gt;Code Organization:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you clone the websiteWork repository, you will see a folder called &amp;ldquo;websiteWork&amp;rdquo; on your computer. Within that folder are many, many subdirectories. The main folders most relevant for editing, however, are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;content:&lt;/b&gt; holds all the actual editable content on the site; subdirectories within this folder are named to indicate which sections of the site they house information on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;config:&lt;/b&gt; holds the more administrative, website configuration files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;static:&lt;/b&gt; holds images and other files such as publication odds or profile cv&#39;s for reference by other folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;layouts:&lt;/b&gt; the main back-end of the website that holds all style sheets, and design of the site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; Do NOT ever edit the public folder in this repository&lt;/b&gt; It handles the automatic deployment to the main website and should not be edited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/&#34;&gt;managing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; content see the Hugo Academic &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34;&gt;source documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;make-edits-without-deploying&#34;&gt;Make Edits without Deploying&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if you want to just play around and see how something will look before actually deploying to the website?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a version of the website&amp;rsquo;s code (and example code) on DropBox. This code is not live and can be run locally. Enter the &lt;b&gt;lmclSite&lt;/b&gt; folder via the terminal and then type the command&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next open a web-browser and type&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;localhost:&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1313&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The code will render in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For access to the DropBox code, contact Dr. Slevc and you will be granted access for editing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
